Trent Howe

🗣 Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, United States 🛮 tch40@pitt.edu 🗖 (814) 931-7595 🛅 in/trent-howe 📥 https://trentchowe.github.io/

SUMMARY

Software engineer with 1 year of experience interning at Philips with a solid understanding of software engineering principles. Experienced in developing software applications and component tests. Seeking early career opportunity to develop products and grow with other engineers.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

University of Pittsburgh · Pittsburgh, PA · 2023 · 3.3 / 4.0 GPA · Certificate in Quantum Computing and Quantum Information

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern Philips

May 2021 - August 2022, Pittsburgh, PA

- Refactored legacy microservice component tests in Java using RESTful API's to separate testing framework built for simpler, easier to read tests, improving test failure rate from 5% to 0%.
- · Helped create a new onboarding curriculum for remote new hires and helped shape it for future employees in hybrid/remote positions.
- $\cdot \ Gained\ experience\ with\ the\ Agile\ Scrum\ Methodology\ by\ actively\ participating\ in\ daily\ stand-ups\ and\ sprint\ rundowns\ in\ a\ team\ of\ 6.$

Teaching Assistant

University of Pittsburgh

September 2020 - May 2021, Pittsburgh, PA

- · Assisted teaching 2 semesters of Engineering Computing courses (in C and MATLAB).
- · Held weekly office hours to help 45 students with understanding and completing programming assignments.
- · Evaluated/graded data structure homework, projects, and examinations for students, providing constructive feedback.

PROJECTS

Article Summarizer

May 2023

- · Created a website using JavaScript and React that utilizes Open AI's ChatGPT to summarize any news article.
- · Utilized ReduxJS for frequent app updates and pinged an Article Extractor API for data analysis using a reducer.
- · Locally tested and deployed using ViteJS, and then deployed the final version onto a Netlify website.

Job Search App

April 2023

- · Created an app for iOS/Android using Javascript with React Native for multi-platform deployment.
- $\cdot \text{ Tested and deployed using Expo's npm package and CLI for live app updates during testing phase.} \\$
- · Used calls to the JSearch API for new job listings using Node.js Axios.

Pittsburgh Train Extension

February 2022 - May 2022

- · Designed a simulation of a functional train extension to Pittsburgh with a team of 4.
- · Created an interactive train and track model, as well as a live routing system using optimal pathing for 78 different stops.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Developed a Qt UI for the user using the Model-View-Controller design pattern.

INVOLVEMENT

Business Manager

University of Pittsburgh · Pitt Quidditch Team · September 2019 - September 2022

- · Orchestrated successful fundraising campaigns raising >2000 dollars over 2 years, ensuring our ability to travel to USQ Nationals in Utah.
- · Handled budgeting, resource allocation, and financial planning for hosted tournaments, accommodating 5 opposing teams.

SKILLS

Back End: Java + JUnit (Industry experience), C++, C, Python (Academic) Front End: Javascript, HTML/CSS, React, React Native, Qt UI (Personal projects + Academic) Technologies: Git, Jira, IntelliJ IDEA, Gradle (Industry experience), VSCode (Personal projects)